A Guide to the Riddick Family Papers, 1734/5-1804
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Riddick Family Papers, 1734/5-1804
The Library of Virginia
29989
.46 cubic feet
Riddick Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 26 April 1978, of Claudius James Riddick of Suffolk, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The Riddick family was a prominent family in Nansemond County and Suffolk, Virginia. The Riddicks owned extensive property in the county and town and intermarried with other prominent families of Nansemond County including the Norfleets and Prentises. Moses Riddick (ca. 1715-1799) was the father of Jethro Riddick (ca. 1741-1799).
Scope and Content
$$aPapers, 1735-1804 of the Riddick family of Nansemond County, Virginia, consisting of deeds, 1734/5-1804 for property in Nansemond County; a plat, 18 June 1765, of 88 acres in Nansemond County disputed between Moses Riddick and John Jones; a bill of sale, 29 June 1767, for a female slave from Henry Bates to Moses Riddick; and an account, 1788-1789, of Jethro Riddick to Josiah Riddick (b. 1748) for payment of taxes. There are typed transcripts of all items, except for the plat, 18 June 1765, and the account, 1788-1789.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Louise Withers Ellyson Anna Mary, 1958 (LVA accession 31778).
Riddick Family Papers, 1720-1856 (LVA accession 23846).
Riddick Family Papers, 1798-1860 (LVA accession 28524).
Riddick Family Papers, 1806-1981 (LVA accession 31819).
Contents List
- Deed, written 15 March 1734/5 and recorded 26 March 1735, for 222 acres in Nansemond County from Samuel Smith to Richard Newsam.
- Deed, written 28 July 1736 and recorded 28 June[?] 1736[7?], for 150 acres in Nansemond County from Walter Price to Moses Riddick (ca. 1715-1799).
- Deed, written 5 May 1746 and recorded 9 June 1746, for 103 acres in Nansemond County from Richard Nusum [Newsam?] to Charles Jenings.
- Deed, written 27 December 1762 and recorded 10 January 1763, for 250 acres in Nansemond County from Thomas Gwinn and John Gwinn to Moses Riddick.
- Plat, 18 June 1765, of 88 acres in Nansemond County disputed between Moses Riddick and John Jones
- Bill of sale, 29 June 1767, for a female slave from Henry Bates to Moses Riddick.
- Deed, written 8 June 1767 and recorded 10 August 1767, for 112 acres in Nansemond County from John Jones and Philisha Jones to Moses Riddick.
- Deed, written 19 February 1788 and recorded 15 April 1788, for 400 acres from Abraham Sumner of Gates County, North Carolina, to Jethro Riddick (ca. 1741-1799) of Nansemond County.
- Account, 1788-1789, of Jethro Riddick to Josiah Riddick (b. 1748) for payment of taxes.
- Deed, written 6 June 1804, for 60 acres from John Norfleet to Joshua Harrell.